good morning scobie's so I haven't done
one of these in a bit I figured I would
do one this morning and keep you guys up
to date so I'll first off the Maverick
uh Devo is the only time you're gonna
see me not shilling per my own merch
I am shilling for Logan Paul's March so
throw out this weird
all right all the scope is get in here
yeah no we missed you too um so a few
things I want to talk about uh what's
first okay I promise I promise this this
periscope will not all right bro your
your band ID that's just get out of my
Scott now you're out
uh the first thing I want to talk about
I do it with Davin the minutes
definitely matters yeah um all right so
no the first thing I first thing let's
talk a little bit about Gio I promise
that this whole periscope will not just
be me making fun of GM I do promise that
but I saw a post on random
as opposed to random I'm working on
grape and affirm well I'm not shilling
for any bitcoins today um Tesla is about
to suffer the same fate as Ford and you
know this is this is this is just a
fascinating like it's so clear to me
what journalists don't understand I say
it here like Tesla views their car as a
computer on wheels if you go back to
2007 smartphones souls there's a
Wikipedia page that goes into this list
of best-selling mobile phones so if you
look here there were actually there was
a phone that outsold the iPhone it was
called the Nokia n95 and you look at
this and if the year is 2007 you don't
really know which one is gonna win if
what you're looking at is features if
you're comparing the n95
to the iPhone based on like features
they actually look surprisingly similar
so let's let's bring up the Wikipedia
page for the iPhone 2g and actually do
this so you know if you look at if you
look at the CPU if you look at the
memory they're really they're really
very very similar the n95 has has more
memory or more storage similar CPUs but
what was the difference right why did
the I end up out competing the 95 to the
point that Nokia went out of business
climate change isn't ruining everything
you guys can can you can can somebody
tell me like one way in which their life
has actually been ruined by climate
change
um but they're not going off on that uh
Tesla is following a car is super Chris
is pretty nice super Chris is pretty
nice but it's one of these things that
doesn't scale test the will scale to to
at least probably level three with with
with what they have in the cars
um Wow you can't believe I said that
yeah but so just just like like I really
I
um no the coughing in china the
pollution in china's are a problem yes
said climate change' the yeah so that's
that's that's that's that's GM but
that's not what i'm going to talk about
today i'm here to really update you guys
on production so we're gonna go into the
stockroom i've decided in the interest
of transparency to show you numbers so
here are a whole lot of phones that were
unboxed um this is our first production
on this is our production run for the
first quarter of the year so just so you
can see this is our manufacturing
operation here we got all the phones
unboxed so these are the bags that ship
with the with the eon yeah we're what
we're doing it we're doing it uh so
there's gonna be some yeah i'm so yeah
we're gonna ship out hopefully wednesday
let's let's commit to the scope ease if
you buy if you've bought an eon
it's gonna ship out pandas right now are
a little bit delayed what was this a
return yeah we have for you got for you
yeah we got for eons returned oh wow we
got it we got it we got a refurbished
those will ship out me we have people we
also not have internal stock which will
show you guys too
we're thinking about maybe adding these
things as sk news so this is a this is a
space networking adapter and you can use
this to get ethernet on your eon a
volkswagen giraffe so i think i've
talked about this
um we are not going to support any other
cars besides honda toyota this year yeah
everything else will be will be
community oh good you got your panda
this week good um yeah we're a little
we're a little short on pandas um but
macro fab macro fabs gonna pull through
for us and we're gonna get we're gonna
get we're getting ten thousand pandas
they're coming in beautiful injection
molded cases so if you ordered one
it'll still be in the 3d printer case
but the new ones are going to be
injection molded I'm just saying like my
day-to-day there's problems and none of
them are causing climate change so no no
you can use Ethernet so I'll show you
I'll show you another kind of common
stock item yeah we are producing great
pandas at the office
here's another here's another internal
item this uses two pandas to connect a
computer to an eon for debugging would
go that far I mean it's real it's just
the effects aren't you know killing me
tomorrow there's things that actually
might kill me tomorrow and those things
are scary like nukes MA iron ship
look at these gray panda oh I got to fix
my fire alarm you're absolutely right
just like stick your hand in like a big
box of filter mouth that's pretty cool
yeah so yeah we're doing great panda
production here do we have a new case to
show the scope ease for the great Panda
greater collaboration Rick Perry as fast
mm-hmm see what the information we can
get from the blinds both sensors so this
is a radar reflector we bought off
Amazon we're using it to try to trigger
the toyota software to return some some
information I don't know yeah something
with more information how do you mental
health the tripod I just used a
double-sided tape nice very janky yeah
so that's the set up today
you ever seen boxes of phones like this
is 80/60 for new phones this is like
each one of these is a phone grows have
you ever fired somebody fired a few
people you know you don't perform you
get fired that's just how it is
what else we got
these are pause if you haven't seen
pause you can use these to reflash your
pangas
here's Aeon production I got all these
things coming off the 3d Center we got
giraffes giraffes are in stock many
giraffes in stock do we get the phone
straight from Foxconn no no we buy them
through oneplus
Oh late shades you can stop less now and
I'm not talking about those today we're
not talking about those today do you
still need pause you don't need a paw
if using your panda but you do need a
paw if you are trying to if you break it
basically if you brick it to the point
that it won't boot into the st2 get into
to get into bootloader mode yeah so this
is this used to be the headquarters of
crypto scams LLC but yeah guys thanks
for joining the periscope today just a
little some day update about where we
are what we are doing
arrested we have a whole lot of cables
as well does anyone want us bc2 any
cables we have we have many many of them
um but yeah thank you for thank you for
for joining what's let's let's take one
more look at a midnight black midnight
lucky on over on my desk let's just take
a look at it and admire it's midnight
blackness I'm drinking Mountain Dew Code
Red
they should pay me they really should
pay me when I show for their stuff um I
bought this dead stereo camera so
hardware is kind of nice I was a little
bit disappointed with the software the
semi global matching okay now we know
the gray panda case no we don't sell the
ealing case we only sell complete eons
how many young sweatshop labor is
already signed up the eon is it is a
very nice minimum-wage job um assembly
um a grape and a shipping date so I
think we said four to twelve weeks and I
think that will be uh will be true um do
come employees work seven days a week I
work seven days a week most people
around here work six but sometimes
people never sell people will people
hustle hard man we gotta we gotta win
look at look at look at the midnight
black us twenty-five hours of day that's
right I don't know I work constantly
life is work you guys win um is it all
Python yeah what soured well not neon
Timothy couldn't take a present paid
hourly is it all Python the neural
networks no is this gonna be every
weekend yeah we could try to do Sunday
updates see kind of what we're up to
oh we were drawing we were drawing
bicycles on the board what do I consider
a win um I mean winning right shipping
the best system to the most people
so I'm gonna spend my day so here I have
over here this is this is a Toyota Prius
ECU and
[Music]
unless I could talk about that and yeah
I'm gonna try to hack it so we can
update our rav4 to work in stop-and-go
traffic and that would be my project for
today I've put a bit of time and do it
so far it's not that easy Toyota has
better security than Honda but not
because it's like good security like
they didn't like like understand how
you're kind of supposed to do this stuff
they just made up better crap um so
there's that but yeah thanks thank you
thank you for joining uh and I will see
you all I don't know maybe we'll do a
midweek periscope me a little something
cool to show off rest of the Toyotas
okay that's the band question um can we
not send crews pushed up by iana people
live in the well you have people live in
the office the band question is whether
the car is gonna be supported the truth
is guys open pilot is is open source so
if you want your car to be supported you
can write your own Oh Navigant oh now
I'm not on Navigant Board of Navigant
the people who think Ford is doing well
on Tesla's lagging behind looking for
Life team , that's right team , no you
need like yeah team , we gotta like make
that a thing you know it's better than
Jake polish it's not as good as low gang
but like what is it Jake Paul er
well I assist ER laborers with ECU
flashing no what can i we're gonna open
source our ECU flashes if it's the
engine control module not the steering
modules alright because the worst thing
the absolute worst thing that can happen
if you bad reflash your engine thing is
unintended acceleration and that's
nowhere near as bad as like torque on
the steering wheel unintended
acceleration you can the brakes beat out
the gas on any car and that's assuming
things like neutral and the power button
don't work which I'm not sure how how
integrated these things are but ECM mods
are also something that's much more
accepted there's plenty of companies out
there that are already doing like East
you tunings where they remake where they
change like the the tables which it's
the same reflash we would do in order to
remove the low-speed restrictions no I'm
not mad at for because they have Sony in
them
I'm mad at Ford because of how they do
their marketing and branding right I
just read something Oh Bill Ford is
smart cities may be closer than we think
stop talking about that stuff like talk
about what you're actually gonna ship in
in a few years I'm talking about what's
real don't don't give me PR hype I
really don't like PR hype our active is
lame apt it was okay bro I got a lift
more bro I should get more Olympic after
was okay I've met Glen Davos um he's
better than most he's he's a lot better
than most their demo was nice at CES
this year Oh
great pain the case is pretty incredible
I'm more seamless than any kind of case
ever designed before I think it's my
best work but but Eddie it's not great
it's easy Oh so guys we're low on gray
filament so we're prototyping in white
to preserve filament we have a lot of
white filament we have too much white
filament so we have to use some white
film in prototypes it will be great
don't you worry the LED shines through
really nicely
dude this square you still got that no
no buddy whatever shape we want we're
printing from this side oh we gonna put
common Pamela Maggie whatever we want
yeah it's a white print endless but look
at that look at Billy's are endless but
no no like she really show him how
seamless it is it is literally can't see
it well don't even show them where the
see Michelle the other thing you try and
find the Sun like pharmacy that's right
it's pretty incredible and you know how
we got to this case design very
penthouse constraints to be in the red
again this antenna zoomed out of the
great fan of case we couldn't do the
sliding that we used to do oh no this
led to the newest innovation that come
here you want to do a fun challenge on
the board Oh Neil gave this to me and I
was surprised kind of how bad I did so I
raced a ping and then draw a bicycle
erase this yeah no no that was the power
truck but um draw basically yeah draw
bicycle I I'm surprised how badly I did
oh and then I tried to build stairs and
I didn't even worse at that okay well
how you make stairs okay okay the
mainframe like another bar here and
[Laughter]
okay okay where's the seat that's not
important those get stolen a lot of
times that's right okay okay so I've
never actually seen a bicycle that has a
frame that looks like that oh no - one
thing here might look weird - yeah there
is something there are Eddie's doing the
job bicycle what we're on the path we're
on the periscope so if you don't want to
be on that you're gonna be a little cars
go it turns out that all bicycles are
two triangles like you don't even see it
until you like lock but like what that's
a trying like that yeah
triangle hey viv is not here so we have
we have employees at common a I who you
guys don't really know because they're
secret yeah kind of similar to that I
don't know it was pretty set on that
board what I really missed was the fact
that the seat bar goes all the way down
to the pedals like and that's almost
true on every bike yeah well I let other
self-driving car companies use our
self-driving hey guys it's open source
Bros bicycle challenge
thoughts on Chris Chris Latner laughs
Tesla I don't know what he's working on
right now I the guy from Omaha come
through who can you tell who's using it
I mean I don't care like that's the
thing right you know this is I got I've
got arguments on Twitter about this no I
I did see that I did see that I think
that's a great use of his talents um
Chris Ladner wrote I wrote like the the
first iteration is Swift did a lot of
LLVM improvements all the nullify guy
yeah we never ever interview with him I
think I think Tuesday oh we got it we
got an intern for the summer too excited
about but here's the thing right you buy
the hoodie for 250 guys hoodies are back
hoodies are back at 129 what is your bag
at 129 and actually we're gonna remove
the lid from the site hoodies are gonna
be hoodies are gonna be super rare we
are gonna put up some t-shirts pretty
soon yeah yeah cool um look I don't like
use our stuff don't either stuff I don't
care I mean like I like you guys using
it if you want to contribute positively
to the community I'm a fan if you want
to like be a consumer go consume some
other people's stuff pink hoodie yo I
mean I gotta step up we gotta step up
our merch game we got it we got to step
up our merch game copy it's good from a
purchase yet no no yes look what we got
on the board it's everyday bro what's
our next big feature milestone for open
pilot so we're shipping we're shipping
the gray pandas out and then we're gonna
really focus on the localizer and once
we have a good localizer we already have
HD maps which I told you guys we're
gonna open source by the end of the year
we're gonna open source our HD maps and
you are gonna be able to add in traffic
lights and stop signs - I'm gonna have a
million points localizers there be field
tested right now no known as a million
points I guess there's no free hoodies
but better than open street view I mean
we have video back none of them are
really getting video instead of I was
driving to build Maps
yeah yeah follow your common point
suppose could we scrape the data from
ways know what I got to scrape any data
from ways we don't have to we have
everything we need to build a map the
truth is like I don't care what the name
of a street is right yeah we have we
have we have stoplights we're working on
stoplights how can we contribute to
localize our data to script ASAP so we
have a we have a very complex localizer
we're building on the back end here it's
almost better than you buy a yawn and a
gray panda you're gonna get a better
localizer than a plan X um do I think a
map is necessary in the long term I
think map is a good idea
even if you have a car that can drive
without a map and our car will be able
to drive without a map you still want
one because it's an added degree of
safety right if you can if you can
remove 9 out of 10 of your dis
engagements by looking at the map and
being like no cars ever done that before
model you're probably wrong that's
that's a good deal how many more pieces
of hardware will you have to buy I mean
it all depends on like to get to full
self-driving more obviously nobody
nobody believes that single front-facing
camera can get you all the way to level
4 but all of the hard problems in
self-driving cars can be solved with a
single forward-facing camera detecting
whether there's a car on the side of you
is not a hard problem deciding how to
read complex situations at distances of
like 50 to 100 meters ahead and deciding
what to do that's the hard problem or
you're giving out free bitcoins you go
to telecom something some bitcoins viola
free bitcoins um any problem with video
only got recorded one direction no no
all videos good yeah coming I will we're
into level 4 I mean you guys know it
what everyone's working toward level 4
eventually the only question is whether
you're gonna stay in stealth mode until
you ship level 4 or you're gonna ship
intermediate milestones and we've opted
to ship intermediate model
don't a lot of people are thinking look
here's one way to look at it right
here's a here's a difference between
between like whammo and Cruz versus
awesome Tesla every time way mo and Cruz
want to add a car to their network it
costs them money every time we want to
add a car or test the ones to add a car
they actually make money and we actually
make money and that's the key I mean if
you want you know how are you gonna grow
a big Network if you're paying 150
thousand dollars per car I mean you
can't you can do it but then you're
taking on investment right you're you're
you're okay fine if you have way mo
money you're getting the money from
Google like that's not a good thing it's
not it's not sustainable um so that's
kind of a key distinction there guys are
keeping me on with the questions no yeah
the phones are fine eons we'll be able
to get HD maps it's the the localizer
can even run on the server you don't
need you in the rental you can run you
can run an API which is something that
we're probably gonna ship this year to
that will send you down basically GPS
Corrections right I take a picture I
know where you are from the map I'm like
or here are the lanes here are the signs
okay let me send a correction back down
you couldn't it's it's a simple
algorithm it can totally run on the
device and if you have a great panda
you're gonna get all this stuff first
but it might eventually come to people
with white pandas too so what a
localizer does is determines where you
are really precisely why don't all
makers buy my philosophy well you know
here's the thing right
you can't view auto makers like they're
like a person that you could talk to
reasonably ranked at the bottom of the
recent report look at the guy behind the
report and then realize that he
literally did PR for Ford for ten years
right like did he stop you know it turns
out it turns out that that um people
high up in the yard now we don't go
there but um they tend to get Logan
Valda slobs are I don't the guys you
want sponsor me more devices yeah I mean
look I'd love to get uh you want to eat
on in the Yeti we can we make that
happen a gray panda what is its benefits
I mean look I'm not I'm not I don't
market you guys like you see what it is
I'll tell you what it is I'm not gonna
tell you like buy it I mean I only shill
if it's ironic it's not even though
automakers want no risk it's that they
are procedural companies right
don't don't view them as people view
them as like a system right imagine
asking the question why like LS can't
concatenate files why does it LS just
just concatenate I mean that's just not
what it does right you have to view it
that's why view the world right a view
the world is like like like systems like
that alright we'll go to we'll go to it
will go to 30 minutes I just want to
know what it does it's it's we replaced
a Wi-Fi module with a high-precision GPS
chip and then we we localize well I'm is
there a way for comma to be more
productive
not really um I mean yeah more employees
yeah if you can find her right employees
right the whole key is the right
employees not more important I don't
know if like jobs that like wow if I put
10 people on this instead of one it
would get done faster wouldn't more
money we'll have more money this year
among employees cost productivity yeah
they absolutely do I really think like
half of Google is a negative a negative
weight on Google if I if I showed up and
I was a CEO Google I would I would fire
half of them all the cars will need to
communicate with each other no they
won't
why how do they communicate with each
other now only my philosophy works
I mean works for what there's there's
other ways there's other successful
companies in self-driving cars today you
know you look at you look at like embark
Vardhan labs right
of approaching this from trucking the
first place you guys are gonna see level
4 is on trucks and until you see it on
trucks there's no way you're gonna see
it in cities so building a building a
trucking company is a good way to
approach self-driving cars if you want
to go b2b no we're not gonna do an IC
o----
you know I've talked about the IC o----
we might uh we might be involved with
crypto in some way shape or form but
like just look at the telegram ICO for
everything I hate about AI cos so it's
not gonna be anything like that have we
tested it on trucks who cares
no no not Eddie
Eddie's been here a while and it's been
here a while mechanical fix on the ps4
the stupid steering know the way it's
called linked backlash you just need to
overcome it by like putting up to get a
bit of a torque to jolt it and then it
will start going it's a controls problem
I need thoughts
okay like who builds engine who build
sky who builds uh who builds who builds
cars engineers build cars right and no
engineer would be like whoa we should
make it drive equally well forwards and
backwards right like that's just the
thing on the surface that tells me
there's really no way you can take Zook
seriously because that base knows that's
right you have like a design space for
cars why would you design something that
drives equally well forwards and
backwards what it goes in one direction
99% of the time that makes no sense and
it's clearly not an optimal point in
design space why is Tesla still not
visit what do you mean by visibly
working my understanding is like who
cares they buy the chips they ship them
in the cars right visibly working oh
let's announce partnerships and do it
would PR do I think overriding the
dangers of AI I don't know yeah I mean
they're overhyped
if it's the kind of thing where like I
don't know you never want politicians
thinking about your stuff it's not
helpful when you are in like talks about
that stuff but maybe it is like in
Miriam's up getting more money and stuff
because it is something really to think
about just not like next year um of
course Tesla is Nvidia in their car
right but you don't need I mean what do
you mean what is the PIO Domino's and
Ford are partnering for self-driving car
Pizza Delivery who cares why don't we
use in video because it's a lot easier
to ship Qualcomm we will I mean I'm not
a postman video cz2 chef I'm talking
about just easy to ship shipping is
really important Tesla's making a chip
is that necessary not at all no
invidious chips are great there's
absolutely no reason to make your own
chip unless you want I mean look you can
always do that as like a leveraging
point like you think about Jeff Bezos
and the meeting with ups where they
negotiate prices every year Jeff's like
I'm gonna start my own delivery service
and UPS like not another era will be
competitive will be competitive but just
like okay you get a pass this year stop
talking to me cycles you're at
motorcycle for fun you don't ride a
motorcycle this is a practical um I
don't know all right cars are too big
cool guys I said it'd be on for 30
minutes one more question
what my thoughts about the Udacity soft
drive a car course there's some good
stuff in there there's some good stuff
in there you know I don't care about
credentialism you can get access to a
lot of the materials for free Oh a
Vienna's next weekend oh man I have you
need to get the same time I see yes
everyone used to be a good time he'll go
this one's kind of fun
I wouldn't like I like three years ago
it's a good time if you know black
married now what am i up to today I told
you guys I'm hacking Toyota's I'm
hacking Toyota's right and I'm playing
with it's hard to aim a phone backwards
and play with that stuff
cool all right thanks for joining see
you later
thanks for coming I follow us on Twitter
tell your friends did that smash that
subscribe button
welcome rage a yeah I can't wait for tax
time by e on by e on every
buddy always chill for your merch that's
right go to shop comedy I
you guys should should buy stuff always
buy stuff always be shilling always be
plugging and always do it for the views
yo I love all you guys you're you're the
commenting I scope is your what makes
makes coming i great leave a like
subscribe team called a hash tag team
comma Y a alright peace